TUCO:
Ha-ha-ha.
What is this? It's blue.
WALT:
We used a different chemical
process, but it is every bit as pure.
It may be blue,
but it' s the bomb.
[SNIFFS]
Argh!
Tight, tight, tight. Yeah.
Blue, yellow, pink,
whatever, man,
just keep
bringing me that.
You' re all right. We' re gonna make
a lot of money together.
Just remember
who you're working for.
What did you say?
I'm just saying, they
gotta know that they're
working for you.
TUCO:
Like they don't already know that?
Are you saying
that they're stupid?
No, I'm just saying.
Okay, so you're not saying
that they're stupid?
So l don' t understand.
Are you saying that l'm stupid?
Is that it?
Is that what
you' re doing?
WALT:
Tuco. Tuco.
Hey, why don't we all
just relax, huh?
[LAUGHING]
Heisenberg says relax.
I'm relaxed.
I'm relaxed. l'm rela--
Whoo!
Damn, man! Look at that!
Look! Whoo!
Yeah, that's messed up.
Okay, Heisenberg. Next week.
[LAUGHS]
[BREATHING HEAVlLY]
Adjusting for inflation
Good state college,
adjusting for inflation,
say, $45,000 a year.
Two kids, four years of college,
$360,000.
Remaining mortgage
on the home, 1 07,000.
Home equity line, 30,000.
That's 1 37,000.
Cost of living, food,
clothing, utilities,
say, 2 grand a month.
I mean, that should put
a dent in it, anyway.
Twenty-four K a year,
provide for, say, 1 0 years.
That's $240,000.
Plus 360, plus 1 37.
Seven thirty-seven.
Seven hundred and thirty-seven
thousand. That's what l need.
That is what I need.
You and I both clear
about 70 grand a week.
That's only 1 0 and half more
weeks. Call it 1 1 .
Eleven more drug deals, and always
in a public place from now on.
It's doable. Definitely doable.
JESSE: Whoa.
No, no. Stop, stop, stop.
[NO-DOZE GRUNTlNG]
Heisenberg!
What the hell?
What's wrong with him?
TUCO:
What's the matter with you?
You can't take
an ass-beating, bitch?
Oh, damn, Tuco.
Shut up!
There's no, uh, pulse.
Do something.
Do something?
He needs an ambulance.
He needs a hospital.
Do something!
You' re smart, right?
Do that-- Do that thing.
WALT:
No, there's not--
There's nothing.
TUCO:
Breathe into his mouth.
No, they don't teach that
anymore. lt doesn't work.
You, come here.
Breathe into his mouth.
No.
[TUCO GRUNTING]
TUCO:
Get rid of him.
Look, Tuco,
we can' t do him like that, man.
Buzzards and rats and all that.
I'm just saying, you know?
It's not very Christian.
That sounds like arguing.
[CLANKING]
[TUCO WHISTLES]
TUCO:
Gonzo, hurry up.
What's the big hurry?
Oh, l-- I just think
we're done here.
Oh, yeah?
You' re done.
[DOOR OPENS & CLOSES]
SAMMY:
Hey, I'm back here.
Hello?
MAN [ON TV]:
Are already married--
Hello?
[INDlSTlNCT DIALOGUE ON TV]
WOMAN [ON TV]:
Thank you to our νiewers--
SKYLER:
Hey.
MAN:
The crash happened
as rush hour began around 8 a.m.
Walt?
Didn't you hear me?
Walt.
Hey.
Hey yourself.
What, you can' t answer
when l'm calling you?
Are you okay?
Great.
New hat?
Yeah.
[SIGHS]
I got some grilled chicken
at Albertson's.
Do you want me to heat
some up for you?
WOMAN:
But they can occasionally adapt
to other local areas
like airports, golf courses--
[TV TURNS OFF]
Where've you been?
[WALT SOBBlNG]
SKYLER:
What is--?
What are you doing?
Okay. Um...
You know what?
I've got all this crap
on my face.
Let me clean up first,
okay?
You know, Walter Junior's
gonna be home any minute, so...
Okay. Um-- Yeah, just...
Okay. Hold-- Enough.
Hold up. Stop it.
Ow! Stop it!
[SIGHS]
I know you're scared
and you're angry and you're frustrated.
And l know none of this is fair.
But you cannot take it out on me.
WALT JR.:
Hey, I'm home.
[♪♪♪]
JESSE:
Oh, we are dead.
Dead, man.
Ruto or rute
or however the hell you--
This is conjecture.
This is conjecture?
Yes. And conjecture isn' t helping.
Conjecture--?
We need to state the facts.
Okay, fine. Facts, then. Fact A:
My phone rang eight times
last night. Dead air,
hang ups every time.
Second fact:
Like 3 in the morning,
I saw that black Caddy of his
cruising my neighborhood.
No headlights.
If he wanted to kill us,
he would've
done it at the junkyard.
What is that, conjecture?
Are you basing that on
that he's got, like, a normal,
healthy brain or something?
Did you not see him beat a dude
to death for, like, nothing?
And that way-- That way
he just kept staring at us,
saying, "You' re done."
"You're done"?
You know what that means?
I will tell you what that means.
That means
exactly how it sounds, yo.
All right. We are witnesses.
We are loose ends.
Right now, Tuco's thinking,
"Yeah, hey,
they cook good meth,
but can l trust them?"
What happens
when he decides "no"?
No.
It is him or us. You understand?
It is him or us!
How would you do it?
What do you mean, how would l do it?
Specifically,
how would you do it?
Step by step.
All right.
Say we set up
one last sale.
This is providing
he doesn't decide
to waste us before then.
Every time we bring in
a new batch, he always
tests the product, right?
So as his head is down,
you know, giving it a snort, just:
Pop, pop, pop!
Pop, pop, pop.
So three shots?
Three shots or, l don' t know, two.
No, wait. ls it two, or is it three?
Two would probably work, l guess.
Okay, two shots.
Two in the chest? Two in the face?
Man, come on.
I'm just trying to understand
how this works.
Okay. All right,
we'll put a pin in that.
But by now,
the big guy, Gonzo,
he's probably coming at you, right?
Yeah.
Right. So you turn toward him.
Yeah, just wheel on him--
How many shots for him?
I mean, he's a big guy.
How many shots
does that take?
I don't know. Three shots.
Okay, three shots.
Okay, Tuco and Gonzo.
Two men down.
Now, is there
anyone else there?
I mean, Tuco is usually
with someone else, right?
Maybe even a couple of guys.
His dealers, his posse.
All right.
So we'll put a pin
in that one too.
Now at this point, how many
shots have been fired?
I mean, you've gotta be running
low, right? How many bullets
does that gun even take?
Well, let me see.
It's not--
[GRUNTlNG]
How can you suggest
that we kill a man
and you can' t even
open the gun?
It's not that easy, is it?
Hey, man, Walt, you did it.
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
MARIE:
Call Skyler.
[PHONE BEEPING]
[PHONE RINGING]
SKYLER [ON RECORDING]:
Hey, there. You' ve reached Walt,
Skyler and Walter, Jr.
We can't come to the phone right now,
so please leave us a message.
Well, aren't you early bird,
up and out already?
Listen, the big lug and I
are gonna go try
that new restaurant
over by UNM tonight,
so let me know
if you guys wanna hang.
Listen to me. "Hang."
Walt Jr. will be proud.
I know the lingo.
I'm still hip.
It's Chinese. The restaurant.
I don't know,
I just feel like Chinese.
Do you think that people
in China ever just feel
like American?
You know, and they go out
and get little takeout boxes
with mashed potatoes
and meat loaf
and try and figure out
how to use the little knives and forks?
I wonder if that ever happens.
All right, l'll let you go.
So call me.
[PHONE BEEPS]
Skyler didn't pick up?
Obviously,
she' s not home.
HANK:
Baby. Baby, wait up.
Hey, what was
that about, uh--?
About Chinese?
Dinner tonight.
That new place.
How late they serve?
I don't know.
You got Dave at 8.
Not tonight.
Yeah, yeah. You do. Remember?
No, that's Thursday.
Mm-uh...
Yeah, l'm pretty sure
that's Thursday.
Remember how at
the last minute they
changed it around for you?
They were gonna charge us
a penalty.
Look, baby,
you only got six more sessions.
And l'm doing them, Hank.
I said I would do them,
and l'm doing them.
I can't help it if you got
your days of the week wrong.
BOY:
Look out. Sorry, Mr. Schrader.
Look, it's--
You know, it' s just--
Oh, boy. I--
I think Dave is, um,
really helping you.
Yeah.
[SOFT lNSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYlNG ON CAR STEREO]
Yeah.
Sorry about that.
She' s, uh...
MAN:
Hey! Hey, where's my
phone call? Ow!
Hits two in the sand,
two in the forest. Ha-ha.
And then he says, "Give me a four."
HANK: Gomez.
Gomez?
What do you got for me?
Come on. Chop-chop.
Good morning to you too.
GOMEZ:
A.P.D. sent this over. This was
about eight or 1 0 days ago.
You know Southwest Aniline, right?
Yeah, off the 25?
The place smells like feet.
This is them.
Check this out.
Holy shit. What was that?
Thermite. So they tell me.
Burns about 5000 degrees.
GOMEZ:
Kind of stuff you see
on a James Bond movie.
Nice.
Guys who know their trade.
Ah, wait. I take that back.
[CHUCKLES]
What, they didn't think
about stealing a hand truck?
Hey, try rolling it, morons.
It's a barrel.
It rolls. Jesus.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
HANK: So, what' d they get?
Methylamine, 30 gallons.
P2P?
They' re cooking
old school biker meth.
Who the hell
still does that?
All the old-timers I know
are either dead or in prison.
Pseudo's in short supply,
so these two make do
by changing up the formula.
That and the thermite,
I'd say these two
know their chemistry.
But ranking them as burglars?
Shit.
I wouldn't trust these two
to break into the
Special Olympics.
They got book learning
but no street skills.
Maybe they' re college kids.
Chem students
trying to make a big score.
Yeah, maybe.
I tell you, 30 gallons of precursor...
That big a score, they're gonna
wind up stepping on some toes.
Tell you what, they better pray
it' s us who catches up to them
and not those boys from Juarez.
[CHUCKLES]
[CAR ENGINE STARTlNG]
[GASPS]
Your daughter wants out.
[PHONE RINGING]
SKYLER [ON RECORDING]:
Hey, there. You' ve reached Walt,
Skyler and Walter, Jr.
We can't come to the phone
right now, so please leave us
a message.
[ANSWERlNG MACHINE BEEPS]
MARIE:
Hey, it's me.
Thought l'd try you earlier this time,
before you go out
and, you know, face the day.
I'm realizing now
it probably takes you a little longer
to get to the phone,
owing to the extra baby weight--
Hey, sweetie.
[SIGHS]
Walt, did you spend
the entire night out here?
No.
No, no. Well, not all of it.
Oh, yeah. I did have a touch of--
My stomach, you know. And, uh...
I knew I was gonna be up and down,
so l just didn't wanna wake you.
WALT:
How would he know where I live?
You sure it was Tuco?
Who else could it be?
Did you ever tell him my name?
No.
Did you ever tell him
where I live or anything?
No.
What about Gonzo, or the dead one?
Did you tell them anything?
I didn't say jack, man.
Okay, Tuco must've put out,
like, you know, feelers.
He's got his ways and means, yo.
Sources, all right? He' s closing in.
And what happens when
he finds out that my
brother-in-law is a DEA agent?
Oh, God.
What happens then?
Look, it's got five bullets.
I finally figured out how to--
Look, l just finally-- l figured it out.
I say we get a second gun, right?
For you.
I mean, don' t we, like,
double our chances?
I mean, mathematically.
I've got a better idea.
Thank God.
All right.
What is it, Mr. White?
Lay it on me.
Beans.
Beans?
They' re castor beans.
So, what are we gonna do
with them?
Are we just gonna grow
a magic beanstalk? Huh?
Climb it and escape?
We are going to process them
into ricin.
Rice and beans?
Ricin.
It's an extremely effective poison.
It's toxic in small doses.
Also fairly easy to overlook
during an autopsy.
All right.
All right. So--
Don't touch them.
You can get poisoned from beans?
Yes.
Back in the late 70s,
ricin was used to assassinate
a Bulgarian journalist.
The KGB modified
the tip of an umbrella
to inject a tiny pellet
into the man's leg.
And we' re talking about
an amount not much
bigger than the head of a pin.
But it-- lt killed him?
Oh, yes.
Now we just need to figure out
a delivery device,
and then no more Tuco.
Oh...
[KNOCKlNG ON WINDOW]
Hey, Sky.
Hey, Hank.
How you doing?
Is this, uh--?
This a bad time?
Um-- No, come on in.
Uh...
I should've called first.
I'm sorry.
What can I do for you?
Maybe, um, we ought--
You wanna sit down first?
I don't know, Hank.
Depends on whether or not
this is gonna be about Marie.
Did she send you?
Hell, no.
She' s barely
even talking to me.
That's why I'm here, okay?
Self-preservation.
Big time.
[LAUGHS]
Look,
I know you gals have
your ups and downs.
I get it.
Gals.
And l need to get involved
like l need a second
hole in my ass.
[LAUGHS]
But if you could do me
this huge favor and just
return her phone calls.
I don't, ahem, think
I'm quite ready to do that yet.
Communication.
Communication, right?
Back and forth. Come on.
Sky, do this for me, please.
You can yell at her.
Just call her back.
[SIGHS]
Marie is a shoplifter, Hank.
That's right.
That baby tiara
she gave me at the shower?
She stole it
from Gertrude Zachary's. Yeah.
I almost got arrested
when l went back to return it.
And Marie won't admit it.
She won't apologize.
Yeah.
If l thought you were gonna
return it, l would have never,
you know...
You knew about this.
We' re working on it.
I mean,
she' s got this therapist, Dave.
And l mean, Dave is really good.
Dave's good, yeah.
But it's an ongoing process, Sky,
and we have gotta be
understanding, you know?
I mean, we gotta, you know.
We gotta support the shit out of her.
Oh.
Do we?
Yeah.
I need support.
Me.
The almost-40-year-old
pregnant woman
with the surprise baby
on the way.
And the husband
with the lung cancer
who disappears for hours on end,
and l don' t know where he goes.
And he barely
even speaks to me anymore.
With the moody son
who does the same thing.
And the overdrawn
checking account.
And the lukewarm water heater
that leaks rusty-looking crap
and is rotting out the floor
of the utility closet
and we can't even afford to fix it.
But, oh, I see.
Now I' m supposed to go,
"Hank, please,
what can l possibly do
to further benefit
my spoiled, kleptomaniac,
bitch sister,
who somehow always manages
to be the center of attention?"
Because God knows she' s the one
with the really important problems.
[SOBBING]
Want me to take a look
at that utility closet?
[♪♪♪]
JESSE:
That's all it takes?
WALT:
That's all it takes.
JESSE:
So now what?
WALT:
Now we arrange
our next meet.
In a public place this time.
Nice and safe.
Business as usual.
And after we sell him
our usual four pounds,
then we'll pull this out.
"By the way, Tuco,
this is a new meth formula
we've been working on.
Care to try it?"
Okay, well, what's new about it?
I mean, just in case he asks.
What do we say?
I don't know.
Whatever you want.
It gets the user
insanely high.
I mean,
how much salesmanship
do we really need?
That degenerate
snorts anything
he gets his hands on.
Okay, well, we'll just put
a pin in that, then.
Anyway, within the next
48 hours, maybe 72,
it' ll look like natural causes.
What, like a heart attack?
Yeah.
Or the flu, maybe.
His associates won' t know
any differently,
and we'll be in the clear.
Not if Tuco kills us first.
[PHONE RINGING]
Ah...
[PHONE CONTINUES RINGING]
Just keep it down.
Hey, Hank. What's up?
HANK:
Oh, hey, buddy.
You been home yet?
No. Why?
Well, uh...
Because I really screwed up.
I apologize in advance for the earful
you're gonna hear from Skyler.
I was trying to get her and Marie
talking again. Big mistake.
I should have just kept out of it.
Yeah, well, okay.
Me and my big mouth, I guess.
Yeah, well, that--
You know, it happens.
It's no problem. No worries.
Yeah, well, thanks, man.
I appreciate that.
Jesus, the wives, huh?
Hank, unfortunately, l really--
Oh, yeah.
Hey, man, don' t let me keep you.
Actually, I' m at work, so--
Oh, hey.
[LAUGHING]
You wanna see something
really freaky?
Well, l would, but--
Seriously, Walt, this is--
[LAUGHS]
You gotta check out this crime scene
me and Gomie are at. Just a second.
[CAMERA CLlCKS]
[LAUGHING]
Hank.
Hang on. lt should be
coming through right now.
[PHONE BEEPS]
Guess it could be worse, huh?
Could be having a day like these two.
Couple of local bulletheads.
Guess they pissed off
the wrong guy.
Walt, you there?
Hey, Walt?
I'm taking this.
No. It's my gun. I need it!
No, you don't.
Not if you leave town.
Get out of here.
Tuco killing Gonzo means
he's coming after us next.
Now, I' ve--
I've gotta get home. My family.
[♪♪♪]
[TlRES SCREECHING]
[COUGHS]
Skyler?
WALT:
Walter, Jr.?
Skyler?
[CLANKING]
[COUGHlNG]
WALT:
Hey.
Where's Walter, Jr.?
Having dinner at Louis' house.
Supposedly.
Yep. All day, I' ve had
the whole house to myself.
So where have you been
this time?
SKYLER:
Walt?
Walt, will you come in here
and talk to me please?
Walt!
I'll be right there.
HANK:
Yeah, l recognize
these two knobjobs.
Known associates
of a psychotic piece of shit
named Tuco Salamanca.
Guess he got tired of associating.
Yeah.
Hey, do you mind if I get in there?
No, go ahead.
Thanks.
The big one smells fresher.
You guys find a death wound?
No?
I see lots of blood,
but no bullet holes.
DETECTlVE:
Yeah. You done taking
pictures?
All right. Let's lay them out flat.
HANK:
Let me get out of your
way here, man.
[CRUNCH]
Oh, snap.
Damn, Ricky.
Leave something for the coroner.
Oh, this is beautiful.
Hey, someone call Jay Leno.
We got the world's
dumbest criminal.
This guy wasn' t murdered.
Look.
Big stuff here
was moving this guy' s body
when the stack
must have shifted.
Crushed his arm,
pinned him here,
and he, uh, bled out.
Poetic justice. Oh, I love it.
Don't you just?
Get a photo of me
with this guy, all right?
Old stumpy, here. Make sure
you get the stump in there.
Walt, would you
talk to me, please?
I-- l don't know where to begin.
[PHONE RINGING]
What the hell
are you doing here?
Get in.
TUCO:
Let's go.
[♪♪♪]